all right so I just started a new 60-day
plan to focus on my health so that I can
bring more to my project to the project
and what I'm mainly doing for the next
60 days is not smoking pot doing daily
yoga and daily meditation as well as
walking in nature three times a week and
focusing on doing it up to a 30-minute
scope on my project and my daily journey
so that I am going live and not stopping
myself but also only staying on for up
to 30 minutes not using it as a new form
of procrastination so this morning was
the first of those 60 days because
yesterday I smoked pot saying goodbye to
it and today doing yoga first thing in
the morning when I woke up Amy I had
this insight the odd time this happens
while I'm doing yoga where I get yoga in
my daily life like how they interact
with each other and today my body was
very sore and it wasn't quite able to do
a lot of the bends it does later even
later in the day and it occurred to me
yoga's designed for all bodies there is
no body they can't do yoga if it wants
to do it it doesn't matter your ability
your size it can be modified for you and
that piece of it regardless of what your
body is when you sit when you are having
your practice on the yoga mat you have
to listen to your body even the
instructor isn't going to know more than
you do on your own body they can offer
suggestions they could ask is this you
know hurting you but you have to do the
stretch to your comfort level you can't
listen to somebody else's comfort level
you can't look around at everyone in
class if you're in the class how do you
mind alone to youtube videos in elevator
and compare yourself to what other
people are doing in some ways I am hyper
flexible and an other way is not
flexible and so listening to my body and
allowing myself to be present with the
stretch and allow it to go only as far
as it's going to go it's not about
looking good to the outside it's about
honoring my body and being present with
it and allowing my body to say when it's
done both
a single stretch like hold it in this
position and even holding the stretch
like no okay they might be going longer
but I'm gonna be done now because my
body will get too fatigued and I
realized that is exactly what I'm
creating in the world is tech Yoga is
like that everyone gets to bring
themselves to the mat everyone gets to
bring themselves to the project exactly
as they are Yoga is talking about bodies
how your body is whatever your level of
flexibility and endurance and strength
it's not about perfecting anything it's
about you meeting your practice and
improving whatever that means to you
whatever way that means to you and it's
the same thing with individuals in the
project or creating that we when I say
meeting people where they're at I mean
that not just physically but mentally
emotionally what you are capable of
doing
no outside person can really dictate
only you can you can't look at somebody
else doing yoga and be like well I can
do that so you gotta like move yours and
your body down further you will hurt
them they will get hurt not listening to
their own body in that same way we all
have our own path to follow we cannot
judge each other's path we cannot judge
like my body's been through a certain
amount I have a certain level of
genetics which means that certain things
are super easy I can I can sit in
certain positions and there is no
stretch for me because those parts are
hyper flexible other parts I can barely
do it and it's painful and so sitting in
that and breathing with it and allowing
it to be on the edge without going over
is my self development technique it's
like doing it bumping up against the
comfort zone instead of jumping over it
finding ways to internally improve that
aren't about how they look externally
and although I don't know if this live
part is going to be there when I when I
go and edit it I did this life because
my iPads not charging at the moment and
also I'm doing it in private so that
there isn't people coming in and doing I
want to come and share more of these
these under five minute insights with
you as they occur and that's today's
yoga insight just if anyway
anyone else registered that it's like
that it's an individual practice that we
are bringing together an individual
journey how we bring those pieces
together to create the tech that helps
us in our own individual journey helps
us because what we can't do for each
other in yoga I can't do your stretch
for you I can't use my hyper flexibility
to help you where you're not hyper
flexible and you can't use yours to help
me we can in tech we kid people who are
good at putting meals together can put
meals together for everyone physically
come and put them together but can give
us the information and so creating a
world that works for everyone it's gonna
be take the little yoga and also be even
better than yoga a better worlds on its
way